Loretta J. Ross Papers, 1956-2005
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. CONFERENCES AND EVENTS, [see also SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS]
  - Advocacy Video Conference and Screening 1993 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - African American Women and Youth Conference 1995 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - African American Women for Reproductive Choice 1989 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - African Women's Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights Conference 2003 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Anti Racism Leadership Training Seminar undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Arab American Anti Discrimination Committee Women's Conference 1988 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Black Families: Confronting the Challenges 1986 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Black Health Historical Perspectives and Current Problems Conference 1990 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Black History Month (Medgar Evers College) 1990 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Black Solidarity Day (Medgar Evers College) 1986 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Black Women and the Academy 1993 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Black Women Gathering 1989 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Black Women Leadership Conference 1990 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Brazilian Woman Confederation Founding Congress 1988 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Breast and Cervical Cancer Strategic Planning Group Workshop 1990 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Bringing Beijing Back: Local Action and Global Strategies 1995 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Bringing Cairo Home: Peace, Prosperity and Democracy 1994 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Building Black Unity: Where Do You Stand (8th National Convention) undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Called to Care: Responding to Hate Groups 1994 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Association of Statutory Human Rights Agencies Conference 1998 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Celebrating Differences, Exploring Commonalities and Building Alliances 1988 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Changing California, Exploring New Challenges for Race and Race Relations 1995 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Colorado Women's Agenda Conference 1987 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Communications Conference (9th Annual) 1980 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Conference of Latin American Feminists 1987 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Networking Together, Minority Women 1980 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Conspiracies: Real Grievances, Paranoia, and Mass Movements 1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Continental Women's Conference (3rd) 1988 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Cross Cultural Black Women's Studies Summer Institute 1986, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 12-13)
  - Dangerous Intersections: Feminist Perspectives on Population, Immigration and the Environment 1996 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Day of Action Against the Contract With America 1995 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Decade of Achievement, National Women's Conference Committee 1987 (Box 39, Folder 16-17)
  - Democracy Under Siege 1994 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Democratic Leadership: The Women Who Ran the '88 Campaign 1989 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Democratic National Convention 1988 (Box 40, Folder 2-3)
  - Ebony and Ivory: History and Shared Vision 1989 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Encuentro Continental de Mujeres 1988 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Equal Position for Women Roundtable 1988 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Equity by 2000: Meeting the Nairobi Challenge, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Feminist Update: A Conference on Racism and Sexism 1979 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Fight For Reproductive Freedom 1988, 1989, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Global Gathering '93, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Grant Makers in Health Workshop on Maternal and Child Health 1992 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Holocaust Studies: Highlighting the First Amendment 1992 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Mailing List for ACLU/RCAR, "In Defense of Roe" 1989 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - International AIDS Conference (5th) 1989 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - International Conference on Population and Development 1994 (Box 41, Folder 1-4)
  - International Conference Reinforcing Reproductive Rights 1993 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - International Development Conference 1987 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - International Health Conference 1994 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - International Interdisciplinary Congress on Women 1987, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - International Meeting of Women and Health
    - 5th, and 6th, Costa Rica and Philippines, 1987, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - 7th, Uganda 1993 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - International Safe Motherhood Conference 1987 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - International Women's Day 1988, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Linking the International and Domestic Dimensions of Women's Issues 1994 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Marcus Garvey Centennial 1987 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Symposium 1986, 1987, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Meeting of Black Women in the Americas 1888 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Ministry in the Midst of Hate and Violence 1995 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Minnesota Pro-choice Rally 1989 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Mobilize For Women's Lives 1989 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - National Conference on Family Violence 1989 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - National Conference on Women and HIV Infections 1990 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - National Conference on Race and Ethnicity in American Higher Education 1995 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - National Conference on Women and the Law
    - 17th, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - 18th and 20th, 1987, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - National Hispanic Women's Conference 1980 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - National Policy Institute 1988 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - National State of the Race Conference 1994 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - National Women's Conference, Houston 1977 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - National Women's History Week 1983 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - National Women's Music Festival 1993 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Parallels and Intersection: National Conference Against Racism 1989 (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - People and the Planet 1994 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Reproductive Laws for the 1990's, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Resurrection '81: Dare to Attempt, Dare to Accomplish 1980 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Rosie Jiminez Commemoration 1987 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Schumer Summit on Paramilitary Extremist Groups 1995 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Sex Panic: Women Censorship and Pornography 1993 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Solidarity and Diversity: A Conference On Current Issues In the Women's Movement 1991 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Southwest Center for Human Relations Studies Annual Conference on Race and Ethnicity in Higher Education 1995 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Speech, Equality and Harm 1993 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Spellman College Inauguration 1988 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Strategy for Peace Conference 1994 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Strengthening the African American Family 1989 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Suffering In Silence: A Conference on Elder Abuse 1983 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Teens Taking Charge 1986 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Town Meetings on World Population and Sustainable Development 1994 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Tribunal Winnie Mandela 1899 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - 20th Anniversary of the March on Washington 1983 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Unfinished Agenda: Women's Future Under the Constitution 1987 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - U.N. World Conference of the U.N. Decade for Women 1980 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Unlearning Racism Workshops undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Voices in Action 1986 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Wise Use Leadership Conference 1993 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Woman to Woman: Single Parenting From a Global Perspective 1987 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Women Against Racism Conference 1988 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Women and the Civil Rights Movement 1988 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Women in D.C. Government Week 1985 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Women in Today's Africa Conference 1989 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Women of Color Taking Control: Mind, Body and Soul 1989 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Women Taking Charge 1989 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Women Thinking Globally… Acting Locally 1994 (Box 44, Folder 11-12)
  - Women's Agenda 1988, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Women's Bodies: Sexuality and Reproduction 1989 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Women's Global Perspective: Bridging the Gaps in Their Constitutions 1987 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Women's History and Public Policy Conference 1989 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Women's History Outreach Conference 1994, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHCAL MATERIAL AND PHOTOGRAPHS - Photographs] (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Women's International Solidarity Affair in the Philippines 1988 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Women's Policy Research Conference 1989 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Women's Way Conference 1987 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Women's World Conference for the Elimination of Nuclear, Chemical and Bacteriological Weapons 1984 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Work and Family Policies 1989 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Working Women Count 1995 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - World Conference to Review and Appraise the Achievements of the UN Decade for Women 1985 (Box 45, Folder 3-5)
  - World Conference on Women 1995 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - World Peace Conference 1986 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - World Women's Congress for a Healthy Planet 1991 (Box 45, Folder 8)
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
  - Abortion
    - Articles 1981-92, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Black women 1986-89 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Clinics 1987-93, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Clippings 1985-92 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Labor and abortion rights 1985, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Right to Life and Operation Rescue 1987-94, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - RU-486
      - Reproductive Health Technologies Project 1989-90, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Clippings 1986-93 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous printed material 1987-89, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Webster vs. Reproductive Health Services 1988 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - With A Vengeance: Pioneers of the Abortion Rights Movement 1961-1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous printed material 1976-97, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - AIDS
    - Articles and clippings 1987-90 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets and flyers 1986-88, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous printed material 1986-97, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Semitism 1993-94 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Arts 1981-90, undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Biography
    - A-P 1985-90, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - R-W 1987-90, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Birth control, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--National Women's Health Network]
    - Black women 1984-87 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Methods
      - Cervical cap 1988, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Condoms 1983, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Depo-Provera 1984-89, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Intrauterine device (Dalkon Shield) 1983-89, undated (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Natural family planning 1982-93 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Norplant undated (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Oral contraceptives 1985-87, undated (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous printed material 1985-93, undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Black men 1980-90 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Black Women's Bibliography 1987 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Christian right 1992 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Civil rights 1980-95, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Coalition building 1988, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Countries and regions (Box 48)
    - Africa 1984-98, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Angola 1988 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Belize 1988, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Brazil 1986-90, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Burkina Faso 1985-88, undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Canada 1983-88 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Central America 1987, undated (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Chile undated (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - China (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Cuba 1988-89, undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Egypt 1988, n.d (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - El Salvador 1985-89, undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Eritrea 1986-88 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Ghana 1984-85 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Granada 1983, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Guatemala 1980-86, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Guyana, n.d (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Haiti (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - India 1988, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Iran 1979-89, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Korea 1988-89 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Latin America 1985-90 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Mexico undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Middle East 1979-88 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Morocco 1985 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Mozambique 1986-89, undated (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Namibia 1986-89 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - New Caledonia 1985 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Nicaragua 1984-88 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Nigeria 1987 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Pakistan 1988 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Philippines, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES - Gabriela and Center for Global Education]
      - Articles 1987-89, undated (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - Clippings 1988-89 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - National Commission on the Role of Filipino Women 1985-86 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - "NEPA Perspectives" 1987-88 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - "Philippine Witness" 1988-90 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous printed material 1983-89, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Puerto Rico undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Sarawak Republic 1987 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Saudi Arabia 1985 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Senegal 1986 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Somalia 1988 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - South Africa, [see also Angola and Namibia]
      - American Committee on Africa 1985-87 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Children in South Africa 1985-89, undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Clippings 1984-88, undated (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Council of Unions of South Africa 1986 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Project South Africa 1986, undated (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - Sanctions and divestment
        - Shell Boycott 1986-88 (Box 49, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous 1985-87, undated (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - South Africa and the U.S. right 1993-94, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - South African Women's Day 1989, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - South Africa Working Group 1987-88, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Southern Africa Support Project 1986-87, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Transafrica 1985-87 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - United Nations 1981-85 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - United States Congress 1985-88 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Washington Office on Africa 1985-87, undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Washington Office on Africa Educational Fund 1986-87, undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous 1985-89, undated (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Virgin Islands 1979-80, undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - West Indies 1987 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Zimbabwe 1986-88 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Disabilities 1988-90 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Drugs 1974-90 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Economics 1974-93, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Education 1984-92, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Film 1981-88 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Hair braids 1987-88, undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Health care 1978-91 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Health care reform 1987-94, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Hispanics 1980-86, undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Housing 1976-89, undated (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Human rights 1985-95, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Immigration
    - Simpson-Mazzoli Act 1977-84 (Box 53, Folder 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous 1987-93, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Ku Klux Klan 1980-94, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Labor 1992-93 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Mailing lists 1988-95 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Media 1986-93, undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Minorities 1981-83 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Muslim women 1981-92 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Native Americans 1978-99 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Nestle Boycott 1988 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Oklahoma City Bombing (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Peace 1967-92 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Population
    - Articles 1981-94 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Clippings 1986-94, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Population and development 1984-94 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - "Population and Environment, Religion, Foreign Policy" 1993 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "Women and Population Policies" 1993 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "World Population Trends, Population and Development, Interrelations and Population Policies" 1985 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous printed material 1984-95, undated (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
  - Pornography 1982-94, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Racism 1979-96 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Rainbow Coalition, [see SERIES V. CONFERENCES AND EVENTS - Democratic National Convention] (Box 55)
  - Refugees 1980-85 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Reproductive health, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES - Health/PAC]
    - Hysterectomies 1982-88, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Infertility 1986-88 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Pregnancy and prenatal care 1985-89 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Surrogacy 1987-89 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous printed material 1987-90, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Reproductive rights
    - Articles and clippings 1986-91, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - "Reproductive Laws for the 1990s," 1988 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Reproductive Rights Update 1991-92 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Right wing 1989-94 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Sterilization Abuse (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous 1986-89, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Teenage pregnancy
    - "Adolescent Pregnancy in Ontario" 1986 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Alan Guttmacher Institute 1984-88 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - "American Teens Speak: Sex, Myths, TV and Birth Control" 1986 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Children's Defense Fund 1986-88, undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Clippings 1982-92 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Mayor's Blue Ribbon Panel for the Prevention of Teenage Pregnancy 1984 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America 1986 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - "Public Attitudes toward Teenage Pregnancy, Sex, and Birth Control" 1988 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - School based clinics 1985-86 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous 1979-89, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Violence against women undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES- Men Stopping Violence] (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Welfare reform 1986-95, undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Women and development 1984-95, undated (Box 57, Folder 11-12)
  - Women in the ministry 1985-86 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Women's history 1983-90, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Women's rights 1974-88, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Yulanda Ward
    - Clippings 1980-81 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Court documents 1980 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Funeral service 1980 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Howard University and the Black United Front 1980 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Memorial Fund 1980-81 (Box 58, Folder 8-9)
    - Reports 1980-81 (Box 58, Folder 10)
- SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS, The video and audio tapes from the Loretta Ross Papers have been digitized and are available online (Smith campus access only)
  - Audiotapes (Box 58)
    - School-based health clinics (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Teenagers and sex (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Right wing attack on R.R. (Reproductive rights) (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Organizing women of color on reproductive rights (Box 59, Folder 4)
        [use copy available]
    - Legislating for Reproductive rights (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Coalition building across race and class (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Overcoming isolation in women's organizations (2) (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Obtaining the facts and stats on women of color (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Men working on reproductive rights (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Combating infant mortality (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - 21st century technology (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Abortion vs. genocide (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Population control vs. family planning (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Violence against women (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Religion and reproductive rights (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - [missing #16] (Box 59)
    - International reproductive issues (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Contraceptives (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Midwives and naturopathic (naturopathy?) (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Who controls your body? (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Women's movement (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - ERA (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Unions and reproductive rights (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Women of color organizations (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - AIDS and women of color (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - Lesbian rights (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Child care issues (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - Political priorities (Box 59, Folder 28)
    - Economic issues and reproductive rights (Box 59, Folder 29)
    - Medical reproductive problems (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - Talking to teens (Box 59, Folder 31)
    - Midwives (Box 59, Folder 32)
    - National Organization For Women
      - Women of Color Reproductive Rights Forum, Philadelphia June, 1986 (3) (Box 59, Folder 33)
      - Women of Color Reproductive Rights Forum, Chicago October 1986 (4) (Box 59, Folder 34)
      - Reproductive Rights for Women of Color 1987 (5) (Box 59, Folder 35)
        [digital copy available]
      - NOW March (Box 59, Folder 36)
    - National Black Women's Health Project: Black Women and AIDS 1988(5) (Box 59, Folder 37)
    - Minority Women's Conference (NOW?) undated Aileen C. Hernandez (3) (Box 59, Folder 38)
    - International Council of African Women, Conference 1986 (Box 59, Folder 39)
    - National Coalition Against Domestic Violence (Box 59, Folder 40)
      - Rape and Abortion Forum 1986 (Box 59)
      - Conference 1994 (session: "Backlash") (Box 59)
    - [not audio - see Videotapes no. 31] (Box 59, Folder 41)
    - Human Rights Institute undated (3) (Box 59, Folder 42)
    - African- American Initiative Meeting 1996 (4) (Box 59, Folder 43)
    - Arab-American Women: Challenges and Triumphs undated (2) (Box 59, Folder 44)
    - Dora Maria Tellez 1986 (Box 59, Folder 45)
    - Same event?(1) International Protection for Women, Panel undated (2) Plenary III, Chisolm - Fedders-Huerta (3) Mobilizing Women of Color/Legislative Action, Panel, n.d.(4) Medical Abuses of Women of Color, Panel (Box 59, Folder 46)
    - Tuning into Life (AARP) undated (Box 59, Folder 47)
    - Eternal Vigilance: Women in the Struggle for Reproductive Rights, narrated by Polly Bergen undated (Box 59, Folder 48)
    - Families and Work Conference, Helping Battered Women 1983 (Box 59, Folder 49)
    - The Military II undated (Box 59, Folder 50)
    - Role Models Unlimited 1990 (Box 59, Folder 51)
    - Poverty Gap and the U.S. Women's Movement, Nairobi 1985 (Box 59, Folder 52)
    - "African American Women and Abortion," Loretta Ross, Cornell University 1994 (Box 59, Folder 53)
    - "Hate Crimes," Loretta Ross and Dave Berkman 1994 (Box 59, Folder 54)
    - NCASA, Luncheon and Keynote Address, Loretta Ross 1990 (Box 59, Folder 55)
    - "The Global Women's Movement," Loretta Ross undated (Box 59, Folder 56)
    - Loretta Ross in Sacramento 1995 (Box 59, Folder 57)
    - Loretta Ross 1998 (Box 59, Folder 58)
    - St. Louis undated (session 2, Afternoon Panel) (Box 59, Folder 59)
    - CEDAW Training 1996 (2) (Box 59, Folder 60)
    - WSCADV 10th Annual Conference 2001 (Loretta Ross Sunday Keynote speech) (Box 59, Folder 61)
    - "Welfare and Human Rights," Loretta Ross 1997 (Box 59, Folder 62)
    - "Bringing Human Rights Home," Loretta Ross (First Congregational Church UCC, Atlanta GA) 2003 (2) (Box 59, Folder 63)
    - Loretta Ross, University of Wisconsin, Madison 1998 (Box 59, Folder 64)
    - Loretta Ross reproductive rights lecture (with Adltoun Illumoka and Bella Abzug) 1991 (2) (Box 59, Folder 65)
    - Lillie Allen Interview 2003 (Box 59, Folder 66)
      [CD copy available]
    - Second Opinion, Loretta Ross undated (Box 59, Folder 67)
    - "White Supremacy vs. Human Rights," Loretta Ross 1998 (Box 59, Folder 68)
    - History of Medicine 1990 (Box 59, Folder 69)
    - Loretta Ross Radio Show 2000 (Box 59, Folder 70)
    - Unidentified (6) (Box 59, Folder *)
  - Videotapes, Videotapes from the Loretta Ross Papers have been digitized and are available online (Smith campus access only)
    - International Reproductive Rights, closing plenary 1987 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - American Humanist Association, San Diego 1998 (Box 60, Folder 2)